aardio 的正确读写
====================================================
aardio 读音 🔊 ['ɑ:diəʊ] 。 
aardio 本就是专有名词，只有一种正确写法，不需要单独大写首字母。

aardio 专用于 Windows 桌面软件开发
====================================================
aardio 是历经 17 年活跃更新的桌面软件开发工具。
专用于 Windows 操作系统，因此可以摆脱跨平台的复杂性，专注发挥和利用 Windows 的专有特性和优势。

没有跨平台负担所带来的回报是丰厚的。
例如 aardio 的图形界面库就只用了少量纯 aardio 代码编写，而且很好用。
甚至整个 aardio 标准库基本都是用纯 aardio 代码编写的。

aardio 仍然可以非常方便地调用大量的跨平台语言与技术（例如使用前端技术写界面）。
当然，能这样做并不是必须这样做。大多数 aardio 开发的软件，还都是以纯 aardio 代码编写的。

aardio 主要特性
====================================================
1、小轻快，永久免费
绿色免安装，易于学习和使用，生成的软件体积很小。个人或企业可免费用于开发商用、或非商用的软件。

2、丰富的开源库
aardio 虽小，但提供了惊人数量的开源标准库、扩展库 - 这些库基本都由纯 aardio 代码实现。

3、Web 界面快速开发
可嵌入非常多的浏览器控件，方便地使用 Web 技术编写界面，甚至可以调用系统自带浏览器写软件界面。

4、可视化开发工具
可方便地通过拖拉传统控件创建程序。提供强大的 plus控件（开源）可以快速制作出漂亮的界面。

5、支持多线程
aardio 可以非常方便地支持真多线程，并且提供大量多线程函数库、演示范例。

6、完美支持 Unicode
拥有独特的 UTF 自动标记特性，不但完美支持 Unicode，也可方便地处理二进制数据。

7、支持第三方语言
aardio 属于易用性极强的动态语言，可以方便地调用大量第三方编程语言或这些语言开发的组件。

8、专注 Windows 开发
方便地生成独立 EXE，完美兼容 XP，Vista，Win7，Win8，Win10，Win11 等所有流行桌面操作系统。

aardio 开发历程:
====================================================
2004 年基于开源项目 Lua 开发出 LAScript，并随当时的模拟精灵推出，
当时的 LAScript 仍然是一种纯脚本语言，仅支持动态类型，并不支持原生静态类型编程，不能直接用于原生开发、不能独立编写应用程序。
只能用于编写脚本（文本格式的解释执行文件）。

于 2005 年开始基于 LAScript 研发新的 AAuto ，直到 2007 年底才完成第一个版本，启动了第一个 AAU 程序。
经过漫长和艰苦的开发，于 2010 年终于对外发布了第一个公开测试版本.这是一个非常粗糙的版本，工具箱里的控件。
大多都是点击提示“尚未完成”，标准库里也只有几个简单的示例，虽然只是发布了一些简单的范例、没有做什么推广工作，
但还是很意外的吸引了不少开发者，直到 2011 年年底发布 1.0正式版，标准库基本完成，已经可以正式的用于开发软件产品。

至 2016 年基于 AAuto 开发 aardio。
aardio 使用了全新的 Unicode 内核，支持网站服务端开发。
aardio 是独立的、更新换代的产品，重构了大部分代码，更改几乎覆盖到每一个文件。

AAuto 与 aardio 的区别类似于火车与高铁的区别。 
AAuto 没有改名为 aardio ，AAuto 与 aardio 是不同的产品。


关于 Lua
====================================================

Lua is free software distributed under the terms of the MIT license reproduced here. 
Lua may be used for any purpose, including commercial purposes, at absolutely no cost. No paperwork, no royalties, 
no GNU-like "copyleft" restrictions, either. Just download it and use it.

Lua is certified Open Source software.  
Its license is simple and liberal and is compatible with GPL. Lua is not in the public domain and PUC-Rio keeps its copyright.

The spirit of the Lua license is that you are free to use Lua for any purpose at no cost without having to ask us. 
The only requirement is that if you do use Lua, then you should give us credit by including the copyright notice somewhere in your product or its documentation. 
A nice, but optional, way to give us further credit is to include a Lua logo and a link to our site in a web page for your product.

The Lua language is entirely designed, implemented,
 and maintained by a team at PUC-Rio in Brazil. The implementation is not derived from licensed software.

Copyright (C)  1994–2012 Lua.org, PUC-Rio.
Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in all copies or substantial portions of the Software.

THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, 
INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. 
IN NO EVENT SHALL THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER LIABILITY, 
WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.

LuaCOM is available under the same terms and conditions as the Lua language.

Copyright (C) 1998-2005 Tecgraf, PUC-Rio
Authors: V. Almendra, R. Cerqueira, F. Mascarenhas, and others.

Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy
of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"), to deal
in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights
to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell
copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is
furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in
all copies or substantial portions of the Software.

THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT.  IN NO EVENT SHALL THE
AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM,
OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN
THE SOFTWARE.
